<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Atheism | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/categories/atheism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-29T10:54:28-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best closing line ever]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2011/01/17/best-closing-line-ever/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-17T14:30:18-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2011/01/17/best-closing-line-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't get to watch the Golden Globes ceremony. To be honest, it's not really the kind of show I enjoy. But completely by chance I tuned in right at the very end, when host Ricky Gervais said the show was over and started his own thanks. And he closed with --</p>

<blockquote><p>And thank you god for making me an atheist.</p></blockquote>

<p>While my facial muscles were still working of forming the smile, my head was already wondering how the quote would sit with some of the theists who would be watching. I immediately started a search on Twitter and the very first tweet I found was --</p>

<blockquote><p>"TY God for making me an atheist" now that was just bad taste!</p></blockquote>

<p>The tweets that followed were more or less equally divided between those very similar to the one above and others agreeing with me that this was the best closing line ever.</p>

<p>I wonder how you can possibly consider it bad taste though. I mean, if you're an atheist, the quote is just funny. If, however, you believe in a god, then he's just thanking it for something. He might as well have said, "thank you god for making me a comedian."</p>

<p>You can't really have it both ways. Either god doesn't exist or god exists and made Ricky Gervais an atheist. Actually, there are other alternatives, but the people who would be offended belong to the team that believes in a personal god who does this kind of things.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That's how you make atheists]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2010/09/28/thate28099s-how-you-make-atheists/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-28T12:44:26-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2010/09/28/thate28099s-how-you-make-atheists</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A recent Pew poll in the US shows that <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5jhxJz5nrEDuOlI9AR5QUtnImO44AD9IGMHQO3?docId=D9IGMHQO3">agnostics and atheists seem to know more about religion than the rest of the population</a>. That's not really a big surprise as previous similar polls shows similar results.</p>

<p>But even if it's not a big surprise, it can still seem strange to many. To me, the best explanation I've been able to come to is beautifully summarized by American Atheists' president Dave Silverman, for <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2010/09/28/us/28religion.html?_r=1">the New York Times</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>I have heard many times that atheists know more about religion than religious people. Atheism is an effect of that knowledge, not a lack of knowledge. I gave a Bible to my daughter. That's how you make atheists.</p></blockquote>

<p>CNN has <a href="http://religion.blogs.cnn.com/2010/09/28/dont-know-much-about-religion-youre-not-alone-study-finds/">a test with 10 questions from the survey</a>. I can't tell if those are the easiest ones or randomly picked, but I found it extremely easy. Got 10 out of 10 right.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
