<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | robteix.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-29T11:10:56-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://robteix.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Roberto Teixeira]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not a-ok]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/not-a-ok/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T14:48:39-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/11/08/not-a-ok</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a little confession to make: our family is going through a rough patch. Both my wife and I are having problems. No, not between us. And both are experiencing very different sorts of problems. But the happening-at-the-same-time complicates the one-supports-the-other thing.</p>

<p>And to compound to that, I have been sick.</p>

<p>As I sat in the waiting room at the hospital the other day, waiting for some exams, I felt like this is one of the worst times of my life. I feel tired, unmotivated, unappreciated, and generally unhappy. And fucking hopeless. That's the worst part, I suppose.</p>

<p>I also have been distancing myself from friends lately. Ostensibly to avoid distractions in a time where I am having to give all and a bit more to a project I do not believe in. Truth be told, I just don't feel like small talk but I also don't want bring others down to my Dark Hole of Misery. And so I'm trying to keep some distance.</p>

<p>I feel lost. I look at my friends and how they all seem to have it all figured out already. I'm still trying to figure out who the fuck I am. I was so sure when I was younger. I was so fucking <em>good</em> at what I did. Now? I just don't know anymore. I feel unhappy.</p>

<p>I know some people who will be So. Fucking. Happy. reading the paragraph above. This one's for free for you guys.</p>

<p>But not all is bad news. I actually got some good news last night. I can't tell the details although I know some of you know exactly what this is about. Anyway, I now have a set date for it and it's in under six months from now.</p>

<p>I'm actually confident that this will make it all better somehow. Just have to wait.</p>

<p>Sorry for the downer, but I felt like writing something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off-the-something drama]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/off-the-something-drama/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T15:06:50-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/off-the-something-drama</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Right in the very first issue of <a href="http://the-magazine.org">The Magazine</a>, I found an interesting article called <a href="http://the-magazine.org/1/baseball-misfits">Baseball Misfits</a> by Jason Snell. In it, Jason talks about the great divide that seems to exist between the geeks who love sports and those who despise them.</p>

<p>I am no stranger to that. I am one of the geeks who dig sports, I know both kinds and, exactly as mentioned in Jason's article, I have experienced the <em>wrath</em> from the geeks who don't dig sports when one who does happens to mention the subject.</p>

<p>Snell talked about why he loves sports so I thought I'd do the same. To me, sports are just another form of entertainment, like watching a movie or a TV show. One thing sports give me that TV shows usually don't is the thrill of not knowing what is going to happen. But there's also the same cheap thrills as in TV shows with overarching stories: the off-the-court/ice/field drama. I tend to follow sports in which the off-the-something drama is strongest. I love great rivalries, I love to know player X has this or that story that can have closure in tonight's game. It's all fun to me.</p>

<p>I think that's one of the reasons I never fell in love with Soccer. I never felt that the off-the-field drama was explored enough. It may be a cultural thing. Who knows?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In which Rob gets app.net]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/in-which-rob-gets-app-net/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T20:48:24-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/in-which-rob-gets-app-net</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got myself an app.net account (<a href="https://alpha.app.net/robteix">@robteix</a>) a couple of days ago. [Cue the <a href="http://ihave50dollars.com/">ihave50dollars.com</a> jokes.]  Still haven't really used it a lot but am starting to enjoy the discussions about the API development.</p>

<p>I joined mostly to support the idea—which I must admit is pretty insane. But what would the world be without insane ideas? ADN will <strong>never</strong> be Twitter or Facebook, but maybe it doesn't need to be. Maybe it really only needs to be a same environment for people like me. I like it.</p>

<p>They do need a better name though.</p>

<ul>
<li>Posted using BlogPress from my iPhone</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Scalzi's Redshirts]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/john-scalzis-redshirts/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T10:59:28-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/john-scalzis-redshirts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just finished reading John Scalzi's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0079XPUOW/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=itsuptoyoma-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B0079XPUOW">Redshirts</a><img src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=itsuptoyoma-20&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B0079XPUOW" alt="" />. It's funny, sometimes silly, but it's also a page turner. I read it in a few hours, just could not put it down. And Scalzi manages to make something that looks like it's obvious and then give it a twist and another and then another until you go, <em>oh that's the thing...</em> It is definitely not hard scifi! I'd describe it more as a satyrical work making fun—albeit in a positive way!—of scifi. I loved it.</p>

<p>Oh, and it's totally <em>meta</em>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My need for anonymity]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/blog/2011/08/04/my-need-for-anonymity/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-04T16:54:38-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/blog/2011/08/04/my-need-for-anonymity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://robteix.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/abhishekb-4S22MEjXDA0-hd-580x389.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Much has been said about the pros and cons of anonymity lately, prompted by Google+ TOS which require the use of one’s real name. No pseudonyms allowed, except apparently if you call yourself Lady Gaga or 50 Cent.</p>

<p>I have seen many kinds of arguments both for and against the use of aliases and I will not repeat them here. There is however one use of aliases that I haven’t seen stated anywhere and that coincidentally affects me personally. Perhaps this is so because the problem I am about to present is not so common after all. Or perhaps it is common but people decide not to talk about it. I have no way of knowing.</p>

<p>Anonymity is a vital necessity to people with a certain kind of disability, a mental disorder. I am such a person. As some of my friends know and others mock, I suffer from a mental condition called social phobia, also known as social anxiety. I take medications that help me overcome some of the most serious effects and that allow me to do things like write about it on this very blog.</p>

<p>Social anxiety manifests itself in varying degrees in all kinds of social interactions. And the levels of manifestations are not what you might expect. I regularly make presentations without a second thought. I’ve given talks to hundreds of people. And yet, ordering a pizza over the phone is terrifying experience to me. No matter how many times I’ve done it, I still have to “prepare” myself every time. I rehearse, play several unlikely scenarios in my head until I finally get the courage to dial the number and talk to the person on the other side. One characteristic of this anxiety disorder is that rationally I <em>know</em> that there is nothing wrong; there is no risk in calling the pizza place. But the brain acts as if there were. But I digress.</p>

<p>I love coding. I have been doing it since I was a kid and it’s the best thing I know how to do. And then there is open source. Open source projects should be the perfect venue for me to have fun. Except I am scared stiff by the idea that someone might laugh at the code. It came to a point where it is impossible for me to contribute. Then I’ve come up with a solution: an alias. For the past several years I’ve lived two different lives online: one as myself and another as an alias. I keep them strictly separate.</p>

<p>Using the alias, I actively contribute to several different projects. I've published books. And I enjoy it all. And it would be impossible for me to do that using my own name. My pseudonym allows me to work around my condition. It allows me to <em>live</em> my life.</p>

<p>I understand the rationale behind the requirement for real names on Google+. But I also know that the requirement makes it impossible for people like me to be really free on the Internet. So far, Google hasn’t figured out my alias. Hopefully it never will.</p>

<p>(Photo by <a href="http://www.fotopedia.com/users/abhishekb">Abhishek Singh</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
