<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chronicles | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/categories/chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-29T10:54:28-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Holy sh*t it's hot!]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2012/11/08/holy-sht-its-hot/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-08T12:32:37-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2012/11/08/holy-sht-its-hot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I arrived in Cordoba, Argentina, in 2009, it snowed. Not white-shit snow, but just a tiny bit to tell me “Hey man, see how it’s not too hot in here? It’s going to be alright” I was pretty happy about that.</p>

<p>Temperatures stayed very mild through August and September and I was beginning to like the place. I went to Brazil to bring my wife and daughter who had stayed behind until I got settled here. I told my wife that the climate was mild and she was glad. And then we came back.</p>

<p>The weekend my wife and daughter arrived in Cordoba, Argentina, the temperature got to 43°C. An oppressive heat. The following Monday I went to work.</p>

<p>“Good morning,” I said to the receptionist. “So hot!!”</p>

<p>“Yes!” She replied, followed by the first time I heard something I would hear many, many times again every time I mentioned the heat. “But for you this should be nothing, right? You are used to much worse in Brazil”</p>

<p><em>Are you high?</em> I thought. <em>No! No I’m not used to living in Hades!</em></p>

<p>“Er... not really, I never experienced this kind of heat before” and then added the question I was really looking forward to ask. “But... this isn’t normal here, is it?”</p>

<p>She didn’t seem to think twice before shattering my hopes, “Yep, pretty normal.” Turns out she wasn’t lying either. Since then, I’ve seen several days over 40°C.</p>

<p>See, this is what the Wikipedia says about the place I grew up in:</p>

<blockquote><p>  Under the Köppen climate classification, Caxias do Sul features a subtropical highland climate. The average annual temperature is 16°C (60.8°F). In July, the coldest month, the average high temperature is 17°C (62.6°F) and the average low is 8°C (46.4°F); in January, the hottest, they're 26°C (78.8°F) and 16°C (60.8°F), respectively. Frosts are common in the winter and snow can occur, but it is less common.</p></blockquote>

<p>That sounds about right to me. I usually start complaining about the heat when temperatures go above 22°C or so. When I was a kid, I used to say my favourite temperature was 16°C. <em>Not hot, not cold, just perfect.</em></p>

<p>Bottom line is, no, I am not used to these temperatures. But for some reason, every time I mention the heat to someone in Cordoba, they invariably answer me with "but that's nothing for you, right? You're used to so much more heat in Brazil!"</p>

<p>I'm sure there are places in Brazil where 40°C weather is normal, but no, I have never lived in a place like that. The hottest place I've lived was Sao Paulo where, I read just last week, they experienced the third highest recorded temperature ever of 36°C. I then checked my phone's weather app and three of the next five days were going to be hotter then 36°C.</p>

<p>In the eternal words of the lovely Lisa Leblanc, <em>osti qu'y fait chaud!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The day a videogame changed my life]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2012/10/04/the-saturday-a-videogame-changed-my-life/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T12:32:42-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2012/10/04/the-saturday-a-videogame-changed-my-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, as I tried getting my three year-old to sleep so I could play my brand-new copy of <a href="http://www.easports.com/nhl">NHL 13</a>, I had an epiphany of sorts. It dawned on me how much videogames influenced my real-life pleasures. And the story actually started a long time ago.</p>

<p><img src="http://cd.textfiles.com/gifgalaxy/PROGRAMS/VGACOPY.GIF" alt="http://cd.textfiles.com/gifgalaxy/PROGRAMS/VGACOPY.GIF" />The story begins in a rather pleasant Saturday afternoon in late 1993. We went into a shoddy building, walked up the stairs to the first floor and found this rather unassuming office at the end of the hall. We skimmed over a thick catalog of game titles and started picking a few we wanted to try. They were cheap, pirated games. After selecting the titles, the guy there noted them down and asked us to wait. In the back, two guys got some floppy disks and started copying the games for us with <a href="http://www.moenk.de/pages/vgacopy.html">VGAcopy</a>. Nice!</p>

<p>Of the games we bought, only one I can still remember: <a href="http://www.nhl94.com/">NHL Hockey</a>. To that day, I had only a general idea of what hockey was: Soccer on the ice. We picked it simply because the clerk there told us it was good.</p>

<p><img src="http://robteix.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/538253-nhl-hockey-dos-screenshot-title-screens.png" alt="" />We went home that day and probably tried some of the other, now-forgotten games, but then we installed NHL Hockey from the floppies to MS-DOS. We were both hooked instantly! The game had an arena atmosphere that later version never quite managed to reproduce. We did not know the many rules of hockey, we learned as we played. I remember vividly as my friend pumped up the volume on the PC when the game would play an 8-bit version of "We will rock you" while two cartoon hands clapped on the virtual jumbotron.</p>

<p><img src="http://robteix.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/nhl96.jpg" alt="http://www.igcent.com/images/stories/nhl96.jpg" />We played that game throughout that night and into Sunday. It was fast. It was fun. We were hooked. NHL 96 was the first game I ever legally bought. And I've bought almost every version since then.</p>

<p>Back to how it influenced my real-life, playing the game got me into Hockey as a sport. A Brazilian hooked on Hockey? Not supposed to happen, but one likes what one likes. It also indirectly started my love affair with Canada, but that's a different story. Following Hockey was not easy until I found a radio that streamed games and later the League started offering live vide streaming for which I have been gladly paying an exorbitant amount of money for half a decade or so. I've experienced a similar effect thanks to the <a href="http://www.easports.com/madden-nfl">Madden</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NBA_Live_series">NBA Live</a> series, but NHL Hockey will always be a special case for me.</p>

<p>I realized that thru hockey I've made friends, some of whom are <em>real</em> good friends. And all of this started because a couple of decades ago we got some pirated games in a Saturday afternoon.</p>

<p>Want to make a comment or suggestion? Do you feel like you need to correct me for not fitting the Standard Brazilian Specification? Feel free to talk to (or scream at) me, I’m <a href="https://alpha.app.net/robteix">@robteix on App.net</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/robteix">also on Twitter</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chrome and the new Lion full-screen behaviour]]></title>
    <link href="http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2011/08/01/chrome-and-the-new-lion-full-screen-behaviour/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-01T23:19:42-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://robteix.github.com/robteix/blog/2011/08/01/chrome-and-the-new-lion-full-screen-behaviour</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://robteix.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/2687444500_e8beddd5e7_b1-580x375.jpg" alt="Three wise monkeys by Anderson Mancini" /></p>

<p>While I was ranting about the annoyances I found in OS X Lion today, a friend commented he had no issues at all, except for the full-screen mode. I got curious because the new Lion full-screen mode is probably the only new feature I found interesting. What did Apple do so wrong?</p>

<p>The answer: <em>Google Chrome</em>.</p>

<p>Wait, what? My friend was complaining that in Chrome you needed to use a keyboard shortcut in order to leave full-screen mode. That, he continued, was because Apple had given programmers too much freedom to implement the new feature any way they wanted. And he knew that, he assured me, because he had searched Google and confirmed it.</p>

<p>The new full-screen mode in Lion is implemented as a window behaviour not enabled by default, but adding it to a window is remarkably easy*:</p>

<pre><code>NSWindowCollectionBehavior behavior = [window collectionBehavior];
behavior |= NSWindowCollectionBehaviorFullScreenPrimary;
[window setCollectionBehavior:behavior];
</code></pre>

<p>Adding the NSWindowCollectionBehaviorFullScreenPrimary behaviour to a window will enable a small button to its top right corner. When enabled, the mode will allocate a new Desktop for the full-screen app and will also add an icon to the system menu to allow you to quickly leave full-screen mode.</p>

<p>And that's the little icon my friend complained Chrome wasn't showing, forcing him to use a keyboard shortcut. Imagine the trepidity! And all because of Apple.</p>

<p>I tried to explain that the problem was that Chrome's windows still didn't support the new full-screen behaviour but my friend's version of reality was unswayable: Chrome supported the new behaviour and the problem was Apple. He had searched Google to confirm it. What could I possibly do?</p>

<p>Search it myself is what. And search I did. And I found <a href="http://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=74065#c39">this comment</a> on Chromium's bug tracker:</p>

<blockquote><p>Comment <a href="http://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=74065#c39">39</a> by <a href="http://code.google.com/u/rsesek@chromium.org/">rsesek@chromium.org</a>, Jul 15, 2011</p></blockquote>

<p>We had a conversation with one of our designers, and what we're going to do right now is remove the fullscreen button so we don't advertise a behavior that we don't really implement. That change just landed and will hit Canary/Dev channels soon.</p>

<p>Long-term, we're going to implement a proper fullscreen interface for Lion. In this interface, we'll also experiment with having a collapsable toolbar. Until then, fullscreen will operate as it does on Leopard/Snow Leopard.</p>

<p>So there it is, straight from the source. Chromium -- same as Chrome -- still doesn't support the new behaviour. Done. Nothing like reality to end a discussion.</p>

<p>Except my friend would not yield. Apple still needs to fix Chrome and anyone who disagrees -- presumably that Chromium developer himself -- is to be disregarded as an Apple fanboy.</p>

<p>If however you don't want to wait for Google (or is it Apple?0 to release Chrome with the new full-screen behaviour, you can get by using <a href="http://chpwn.com/apps/maximizer.html">Maximizer</a>, which adds the behaviour to any application window.</p>

<ul>
<li>Yes, I do realize that if you're supporting multiple OSX versions and, even worse, multiple platforms, things get slightly more complex, but still.</li>
</ul>


<p>(<a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ektogamat/2687444500/sizes/l/in/photostream/">Image by Anderson Mancini</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
